so there are
uh three or four books we can
use uh one is uh it's okay okay one is
uh the source is a s
oh from
alar je of or ornamental
realization and uh
that verse uh gives the
22 uh so I we memorized this verse in
the
monastery and I also got the
Sanskrit because it's it's fun to study
it so some I'll just read it for good
luck
means there are
22 uh then it comes right after the
definition of
b uh so it's very famous we always use
it all my students know it
means what is the definition
of uh I want to become
Buddha complete
Buddha to help other people all to help
all other
beings then the Sanskrit is sayak
this is the same verse
original then they give the 22 examples
in
Sanskrit
Chandra Chandra Jal
nidi vajra chal Shi M chint ARA nura
kanja mahamar Yana
[Music]
means
22 means
2 these are the
original uh then uh there's a whole book
about it from uh gandan
Monastery and it was written 500 years
ago uh uh maybe this is
uh what do you call
it tongue Chow I
think yeah and
uh then uh first p l explain
it and jets Kaa explain
it and I like Jetson Kaa the
most so I thought we can do that
one uh and uh this book he his first big
book that he wrote
uh he was only 25 years
old
uh
okay so here are the
22 and just we try to finish the
22 uh the root text by
uh these are taught in the
sutras do give means uh in short way and
in a long
way in short in the 22 are are short way
and long
way the first two are
short and 20 are
long so here we go and I think it' be
fun to make a t
t uh to give the
meaning like I like that TKA with the
levels but I think it would be fun to
make a better
one uh okay so this was written down by
a but uh taught
by so first one uh CH so the first one
is uh the body CH which is like the
Earth that's the first one of the
22 and um this is a strange thing um let
me
see the old name
for yeah so it must be this one is the
earth I think cuz the last one is the
clouds maybe this is Earth
the last one is the clouds you know so
you mean the up highest I guess the
lower one is the Earth
yeah yeah yeah I think
so yeah Fair yeah yeah yeah uh but I
think we can make a better one yeah okay
uh or a modern one so the old word for
uh there's two words for
bodh in Sanskrit one is
one
is and CH means
mine means to
grow s right
uh to to get the wish for
buddh so he uh he explains the first of
the first
one let me see
Earth yeah why is Earth this I maybe he
studied it but if he didn't study it I
thought he would he would like
it uh it says
so we say body CH is not a mental
function it's a main
Consciousness is not a function yeah
it's not function of the
Mind General awareness
yeah then there's a big argument about
it but this is the old old
idea that it's a body CH means main
mind and CH means function of the Mind
51 function of the
mind so there's a very famous statement
that uh body CH is not a function of the
mind it's the main
mind and it has two
wishes one for
buddhahood and the other to help
people but so it's like the main mind
that has two
wishes uh and that's why it's called
body ch ch means main
mind CH means CH means part function of
the Mind
51 but anyway
uh the the CH is like the
ground uh the whole mind
it's like the
ground
uh because because that desire to to
become Buddha for other
people uh is the
foundation of uh all all the qualities
of the
Buddha but the mind is the foundation
not the
wishes okay
okay so that's the first one and then
just before the 22A says I will teach
you from
Sutra in a short way and in a long way a
long way it means to uh 20 20 are long
way two are short way first two are
short way
definition then he gets long long short
way two then he gets
20 and that's a long
way uh second one
uh gold he
knows and uh he says that represents
these are all uh to teach
bodh so they are all the wish to become
a Buddha to help other
people they're all the same thing but
different part of that
wish so the second one so the first one
is the whole
mind uh which is like the
ground and then all the all the good
qualities of Buddha grow out of
that like trees grow
then the second
one is
uh the wish to help others which goes on
for long long
time
uh and it doesn't matter that person
dies or you see many lifetimes that that
idea goes
on to help other people by using the six
Perfections and it never
changes uh for many life
times uh therefore it's like
gold uh in in English we call Gold is a
noble metal it means it doesn't
rust Noble metal Noble means super pure
if you put steel
there you know or
copper then after uh I don't know 10
years it will get
dirty gold won't change for hundreds of
years so that wish to help people Life
After Life After Life it's like gold it
never get old it never changes
so that's what the goal
means so
the so those two are like the
introduction and the other 20 are are
details uh
and jeta quot a teacher named har badra
harra and he wrote an explanation of
this
book and that explanation is 2,000
Pages it's a two books in the 10 year 10
year is 210
books and two two whole books are uh
this commentary
and and we finished all those input all
of those books it took 25
years so it's all on the website
free uh okay third
one uh it's
called okay what's that Connie I'll do
it I'll do it all by
myself yeah yeah and that's l means uh I
will I will help all those people even
if nobody helps
me and uh I I don't care even if people
criticize
me then I will take
responsibility so that's a special
Buddhist
idea it's called it's actually come just
before B
and I will help people even if nobody
helps
me and even if people try to stop
me I won't give
up uh and that's like the full
moon so that's the next
one because uh if you have
that strong
intention then uh it's called the 37
qualities of a
Buddha uh they will grow more and more
inside of
you so on the first day of the moon is
black then every day little more
light and then on the 15th it's
full so if we have that intention
personal responsibility
then are those 37 parts of Buddha has 37
parts that those will start to grow and
grow uh so it's called uh like a like
the full moon that's the third
one uh is it in the
painting is there a
sun oh moon sorry yeah he has yeah so
that should be a full
moon yeah yeah they call daa means full
moon
[Music]
uh then he you know some other
day uh these uh 22 are found in by
Buddha in the old Sutra yeah this was
written uh
800 years after
Buddha is 800 years after
bud
but but if we have
time uh you can find all of them in the
Sutra and I I I did it on the airplane I
went and found
them there's a many uh Sutra on
perfectional
there's 8,000
verses there's a 300
verses 700 versus what's the 700
versus and there's
a
8,000 there's
25,000 there's 18,000
25,000 but the 25,000 is called 20,000
it's a funny thing it's a wrong name
25,000 is 2,000 it's really it's really
25 but everybody call it
20 it's an old buddist
joke and there's 100,000
verses then that takes I know 12 volumes
it's 12,000
[Music]
Pages the 20,000 one
uh the 22 come from
that but to identify them is very
difficult okay number
four uh this is
cool let's see
is
the it's like a
fire yeah
fire uh then that's a really long
story so when you study
uh uh we call Kum means three kinds of
knowledge sh means
the direct perception of
emptiness by a person who doesn't have
body and the second one is com so that
means uh Foundation
knowledge then there's lsh which means
path
knowledge knowledge path knowledge
knowledge about the
path and that one is direct perception
of
of emptiness by a person who um Mah bodh
but not
Buddha and the third one is numen means
a knowledge of a
Buddha knows all
things and uh that's the main subject of
B it's those
three we call three kinds of knowledge
and it's actually three three direct
perceptions of
K so by a person
who's they Arya but they are not
body second one
is but not a
Buddha and the third one
is okay uh she give me some
then uh we can discuss those sometime
it's it's
a big subject by my
TR then the prep preparation to reach
those
three uh is like a
fire uh because it burns
the the
firewood of uh the obstacles to those
three kinds of understanding
so the first two of the 22 are
General Earth and
gold and then the other
20 they are going higher and higher uh
so number three is lowest
one and then uh 22 is the highest
one so there there's a
progression so this one uh
fire means what is it
Burning uh the wood which it's
burning it's a
mental
obstacle to
understand yeah so it's cool
uh but it's
uh yeah the preparation to reach those
St so it's not so
high uh you can say five path
right then this is during the first two
paths before you see
emptiness so that fire is burning
obstacles
here what what's happening at the second
one
mustac how do you know you reach the
second
path first path you have a personal
tragedy like my mother died my father di
my brother di one
year what the
second is all the learning you're
hearing about uh yeah someone teach you
the
pen so this is fire is uh at that
time yeah not very high
[Music]
yet
okay number
five
uh yeah we call a gold mine
okay uh like where you
find gold
underground
uh okay in in
Sanskrit uh I can give you the Sanskrit
each time
uh Sanskrit name is a nidi
nidi
yeah
uh and and that refers to the first of
the six
Perfections uh which is
what giving yeah giving so so when you
say gold
mine uh it means how the body sought for
practice is
giving uh then he says
uh you you give you make other people
happy
with uh Dharma and with physical
things
uh and then you teach people who don't
like to give
things okay
uh and it's higher than giving of people
who don't have bodies you
know um the body stop as giving
is
higher uh than giving by other
people because their
intention uh is to be is this should
make me a
Buddha uh so I can help other
people
yeah uh
okay
uh number
six uh is connect to the second
Perfection uh which is
what yeah yeah morality
yeah yeah keep keep the 10 uh right no
killing No Stealing no sexual misconduct
no
lying no splitting up other
people no harsh word
no
gossip no uh unhappy when other people
get
something uh no no happy when other
people lose
something and uh no wrong idea about
emptiness so that's the that's
the
uh ratna in Sans
means a
jewel like three means in Sanskrit means
the three
jewels
then means uh the place where you find
the
Jews so this one is
ratna and one of the five the Buddhist
is called R the yellow one Southern
Buddha
yeah uh so this number six is R it's not
just
Jewel it's a where you find the
Jews and it and it's the Perfection
of perfection of morality
then keeping those
10 anybody keep those
10 that's a
morality but it's not the Perfection of
morality if that person has uh body CH
want to want to help the whole
world by keeping
morality and their goal is I should
become buha
then it's then it's this
one because all of these are mixed with
body
CH all
22 okay number seven I like this one is
the
ocean
uh Thena said this one relates to the
next Perfection what is
that yeah don't get
angry don't get
upset weather is
bad traffic is
bad somebody hurts
you then he says a very beautiful
thing why they call the
ocean he says uh if you have a
fire and you throw it in the ocean or
you have a gun
or a
sword and you throw it in the ocean then
the ocean
just uh stay
calm doesn't care you know it doesn't
like oh you hurt
me just stay calm It
Go the gun and the fire then then he's
like he doesn't care and uh it's so this
number seven
is the
body uh which doesn't get
upset uh even if something uh very bad
happen
suddenly means it doesn't get
upset yeah okay okay number
eight yeah good uh it's like a vadra you
and this relate to the next Perfection
what
that yeah uh joyful Eon or
something nowadays I'm thinking should
translate as
fun you know English is
fun you know like when you have teaching
or when you're doing this and it's 2:00
in the morning they you say let's have
fun you know you know and that's number
four okay uh so that's that's the
VRA then it says
uh that person's happiness about
practicing meditation practicing
Dharma the
demons cannot break it
so in
Buddhism uh this diamond is named
vajra but it means m means
unbreakable nothing can break
it so even if we stay here till 4:00
5:00 and the demon will try to break it
you
know make you
tired make you happy I should go to
bed then uh then it
broke but the body St is uh fourth
Perfection it's
unbreakable so sometimes in Buddhism
Diamond means uh cannot be
broken by
demon then uh
in the tradition in G UHA
tradition uh we don't believe demon is
going to walk through the
door demon is like looking at the clock
oh you know I should go to
bed you know it break the
fun number eight it connect to that uh
Perfection so all of these are
budh but this one has a lot of fun in
it the
diamond unbreakable
fun guess which one is number nine next
one yeah yeah uh I can give him on the
Sanskrit if you
want mountain is
[Music]
the is aala aalala
yeah yeah and
uh let me
see
oops which
Perfection it's
left yeah meditation
and uh he said it should be like a
mountain then when you do this
mandala this is supposed to be the whole
world and there are four uh
continents and this one is
the
meu uh middle of the
world uh big
mountain then uh that mountain Will
Never Move
uh so he he says not just Mountain but
the king of the
mountains and uh then nothing can shake
it it's the in in the yoga they called
Dua the the it's the core of the
world and it represents
the so anyway um
uh when the body suff reach number
nine uh that meditation cannot
shake by
Distraction then he says uh TOA says
what kind of
distraction and it's the same as in the
J Buddha said sh put
sorry uh subi
says how should we
live how should we
practice how should we
think and how should we think means
never be
distracted and in Buddhism we call by by
the signs of
things what do you mean here uh like
when I see round oh
and I see
white these are signs that this is a
cup so in
Buddhism that's called distracted by the
[Music]
signs and it means I believe the cup is
is coming this
way but actually it's coming this way so
usually distraction means two right
one is a mind got too too
agitated and I start to think about
Y and uh or the mind got
sleepy and I'm my meditation like
this you know usually those are the
two but for bod
SAA uh look at the
cup see the signs of the cup
and feeling is coming this
way and then then their meditation
shaking but when they reach this
place uh it's like the Snow
Mountain can never Shake by this this
destruction it's cool very high body
saer okay that's number
nine this is going to go pretty
fast I think so but slow is better maybe
okay uh number
10 is a
medicine the old Sanskrit word for
medicine
is yeah
and it means herb like natural
herb not
chemicals then the Sanskrit here is
O there's only like three Sanskrit words
that start with oh this is one of
them and
uh it it cures
the uh let me
see
yeah there
are two kinds of
obstacles in
Buddhism uh they are called
uh negative emotion
obstacle what's the second
one obstacle to omn yeah obstacle to
omnition
so these are the two classical
uh
obstacles like first one is things like
anger
jealousy
desire they are all negative
emotions uh and they keep us from
Nirvana and Nirvana is different from
Enlightenment
right Nana just all your negative
thought finish
but your body don't become
Buddha then uh second kind of
obstacle uh you cannot see all things in
all times in all
places that's an obstacle to
buddh so these are
very classical two obstacles that we
have
first is negative
emotions and second one stop us from
buddh especially from knowing all
things then uh
medicine number
10 it means that it cures these two
problems uh these two
obstacles so that's how we explain
number 10
so it's not like normal
medicine and all of these are body
CH all
22 so this kind of body CH can stop
those two obstacles cure
them yeah it's always com combined with
that
yeah okay number
11 yeah
uh it's interesting the uh the Sanskrit
here is
uh it's
Mitra like d
MRA yog one of our yoga Min
teachers and it it really just means
sorry it just means
friend but it's an old word for a
spiritual teacher
and that word is a the full Sr word is
what
do the second
half it's called KRA
KRA means uh good de
friend West the Tibetan
oh like what's
name okay so when they made that
degree they chose this
one and then not all G is a good
spiritual friend but
um but the meaning is
that it's a translation of C
and it was a a name for Spiritual
teacher long before the monasteries you
know then this is called the Perfection
of
[Music]
prayer so did we finish all the
Perfections well
six we seven yeah well the wisdom sorry
the last one number
11 we didn't we didn't finish
[Music]
that yeah number
10 is not called the Perfection of
wisdom it's not okay it's called
Uh the wisdom which understand the two
kinds of no self
understanding of two kinds two kinds of
no no no
self first one is a no self of
Michael
person and uh second is
uh no self of of
things so uh
and that's a long debate in that G video
my my llama's asking me a question he's
asking me that
question because they ask you which one
do you need
first should I understand Michael
first or should I understand the cup
first what do you
think there's a very famous answer do
you remember well it it has to do if
you're if you good obain this direct
perception of emptiness the first aspect
of emptiness is the emptiness of Michael
yeah yeah when you see
directly you always he will see
emptiness of Eric he will see she will
see emptiness of Joanna you always see
your own emptiness
first and then later you see emptiness
of things
including your
parts uh but when you study
it uh you first you study
pen because it's difficult to understand
Michael because we are so attached to
M okay
yeah okay uh that was number 10 that was
still number 10 then the so it was
hasn't called the Perfection of wisdom
yet
okay because there are 20 of these and
there's only six
Perfections so there going to be some
other
things okay number
uh is called tapin means uh in English
we call skillful means aaya in in s
spell
and
uh how should we
say it means a small action big
result my Lama used to say
uh in ined they didn't have any
machines and to to cut the
crops they use a sickle on the on the
Chinese flag there's a knife that knife
for yeah then uh that's not tough that's
not aaya it's very
slow and uh then he saw um those
machines he said oh that's
AA it means very
powerful
method so this is number
11 which one yeah it means number 11 is
called spiritual
friend so it's interesting because the
other ones are like ocean or
gold number 11 is a
person uh because they have
compassion and because they know
skillful ways efficient
ways they will help
you J good means
uh in America when you get
married when you take this marriage
commitment you have to say in good times
and in bad times
I will stay with
you and uh that's the meaning
here because the main quality of a
spiritual
teacher in good times or in bad times
they will support that
student and they they won't give it
up
uh and their thinking is effective like
that machine
uh because a one minute of real
body is a more powerful than than any
other
action uh
yeah and it takes the small good deeds
and it makes them big
and uh when people talk about number
11 they talk about
uh when a body suffer there a small good
any good
thing it's like a drop of water Dro in
the
ocean and it's very difficult to destroy
that that J
as long until the ocean dry
up that drop will be there some
place so that also means very
effective and uh and then he adds that
uh a real uh K
MRA uh to help their
student they're happy to go to the hill
and
suffer if if there's a person there they
can
help Okay uh number
12 it's like
aint
wishing you have a list of them yeah
Chinese in the 12 wow cool2 but
different version 22 Yeah okay good but
just for reference I will
transl okay so chint me wish
jeel and if you have
one uh there's a long story how you have
to prepare it oh
prepare you can't just make a wish to
this Jewel you have to do many
things it has to be a certain day of the
month you have to wash it special
way and you have to make special
pray then it will that's a long
story uh but this one relate to the he
calls Perfection of praying
prayer
uh and here's what the prayer says
this this jewel is like a
prayer and here's how he describes the
prayer so you are praying for a list of
things like
a in America the kids will give their
parents a list of gifts for Christmas I
want a bik I want I want a dog
may I achieve the body
of uh may I go up from the the lower
understandings to higher
understandings may I always hang out
with Buddha and
may I learn to sing the one song which
helps the whole
world in this world may the three
jewels uh never be
interrupted uh
may I always respect the
buddh uh and those are the there's those
are the prayer here in this
case number
12 which is like a
jewel because it makes those prayers
come true
so uh
body makes those prayers come
true like the like the
chint okay what number now 13 yeah 13
yeah we're doing pretty
good
uh he calls it to
means it means the Perfection of power
so he he's got more than six Perfections
here because there's 20 right the first
two are just
introduction and they apply to
everything uh Earth and gold apply to
everything okay number
13 it's like the sun
uh because when when the When It Shines
on that person's
students the function of the Sun in
Buddhism is to make crops
grow uh so uh this body CH is like the
sun that makes the crops grow
uh
how uh they like to support their
students so you know there's the 10
Perfections in
Buddhism six are uh you know usual
six and there's four
extra and that's how to help your
students what are they remember what's
the first one s sing do you remember we
talked about it I think material yeah
good yeah give them food give them
money second
one is prise them yeah encourage them
yeah yeah you are so great you're my
best
student I have so many student but you
are the best
one third
one them third one is uh what should you
say encourage them to do what you teach
them so I taught you all these things
please do
something that's called that's the third
one fourth one do you remember that's
the most
famous most
difficult it said do the same career or
something together no it means that what
you say they should do you should be
good
example the most
difficult so you tell them to be uh
never get angry then you should never
get
angry okay so this number 13
is uh first emphasize
uh the first one of those four which is
support
them give them
money
food um make them
happy uh and then finally uh teach teach
your students the six
Perfections and then finally finally
teach all the being the six
Perfections
uh like that that's number what number
are we on 13
13 yeah then UHA says this mainly relate
to you know four kinds of giving ratar
right yellow
Buddha yeah we taught it
in there are four t
for first one
is yeah
things
fearlessness but fearlessness means
treat everybody
equal so give a material
things equinity teach every teach
everybody
the third
one
Dharma and the fourth one is give
love these are four tantric
vals how many tantric vals in the F
Buddha you said 122 no just the five
Buddha oh
just I think it's 19 I think it's 19
I I believe it's 19 I don't remember
anyway this only relates to giving
Dharma and giving things this one number
13 15 number
13 give Dharma and give
things
okay number
14 this one he calls uh the Perfection
of wisdom
and uh it's called Lou Lou means
song then he says a song of cha cha
means
uh pish when you go
uh
oh you know when you give those
toras uh there's a special
pretta called Tisa and Tissa means
they can only eat bad smells like poooo
smell or peee smell they live on those
for food there's one kind of bad
Spirit the Sanskrit word is Ganda
Gand Gand means smell right
then
uh but there's a certain but there's
another kind of
Ganda which is the musician in the
Buddha
Paradise so you have to be careful not
to make a mistake
here it says the song of a
Ganda so if you don't know what you're
doing you will translate it
wrong so anyway they make a very
beautiful
music and the 14th kind
of has the the Beautiful song of
wisdom the Perfection of
wisd
uh because that song is so beautiful
that the student wants to understand k
uh and and after they sing the
song the student wants to learn
and is easy it means how do all things
exist it
means but
means all the stuff in the universe like
what is the color of that planet and
what are people thinking on the
[Music]
Jupiter so it's called the total way of
all things and the total quantity of all
things so the first one is
K and the second one is actually see all
things everywhere understand them like
scientist
[Music]
yeah okay that's
14 that's the
song
[Music]
15 is
King uh the Sanskrit is the nura
nuraa there is I like this word because
the Sanskrit word for
man is
n and uh in in in
Rome the emperor of the world at that
time was
Nero and it means means ner the
man big
man so this root is a the word for King
here is the big
man yeah uh and it refers to uh having
Clairvoyance Clairvoyance means I can
hear what the they are saying in the
reception right
now what my what's Veronica doing in in
like in Arizona right
now those are
Clairvoyance five five
types so that's that's this
body uh
is it's
Clairvoyance and it's like a cling King
because it's very
powerful then uh it it refers to
then he has a list
okay I did it on the plane
five six
seven uh one moment of
body has enough power for he gives one
two three four five six different seven
different
things it can do seven different
things these are all part of number
15 okay so one moment of that real
bod uh is enough to do seven different
things number
one
can can pass beyond all the
planets in the
UN number
one uh then this is cool number
two uh he says you take one
hair
ouch okay you take one hair and uh you
split it into uh 100 pieces one
hair and
uh even if you even if you uh hold it
up uh then there are many uh creatures
living on
that uh
thousands of small creatures are living
on but uh your hand is so
gentle uh that it doesn't hurt any of
them very
interesting
okaying could think were creatures uh oh
by the way it's not that easy
that body SAA can also use 100th of a
hair uh can put it under the an
ocean and lift up the
ocean uh on a million planets at the
same
time yeah
and the water won't be disturbed all the
animals living in the those oceans they
will be happy you know he's they he will
lift up the ocean from those planets
with one
hair and they're all happy nothing
happened to
them I caught one roach in uh we had a
terrible hotel in Hong Kong
this room is so nice thank
you we had a roach coming out of the
bathtu you
know I'm taking the toilet paper you
know that's why I need extra toilet
paper sorry I didn't yeah you didn't
give
me I'm picking her up you
know then one I I heard him you his
leg so the voice St can lift
one million
ocean none of that doesn't hurt then
there are billions of billions of small
creatures inside the ocean
right he doesn't hurt
them then at the end in Abid third
chapter at the end of this of this
world uh and scientist say same thing
the sun we call Super
NOA in in in in Abid says uh 700% grow
seven times
normal and in the beginning it will kill
all the
people too H then it will
dry all the sorry kill all the
plants and then all the oceans will dry
up and then the mountains will
melt and then finally that planet will
uh but the body suffer at this level
15 that fire he can go and it will
stop
it okay that's number that's the third
one
uh then at in the end of the world
there's also a very strong
wind that destroys all the
buildings then that body can go like
this and finish
it that's the fourth part
uh are you still a bu
suff sounds like
yeah but you're getting higher and
higher so 15 is pretty
high then he said something I don't
understand
completely it says with one
Kil uh you can feel the the sky on a
million planets K means when you cross
your
legs you know when you go like
this that's
called and uh I don't understand this
part and I didn't have time to check oh
can you repeat this yeah uh
one uh can fill the
sky on a million planets
so I have to study this one I don't I
don't understand
it yeah I don't I'm not sure what he's
talking
about sometimes one K2 means just to sit
in meditation one
time like sometimes we say in one K I
will become Buddha and you refuse to
move until tell you
finish but I I I don't understand I
don't know why it fills the sky I'm not
sure I didn't have time
to I didn't have time to
study okay now this one's are funny
number 16 15 a b c d e the sixth part of
15 sixth part of
15 uh if you take one
hair and uh you tie it on the snow
mountains of planet
you can pick up the
planet and just throw
it okay let you take one here and tie it
on the plantet on a mountain youd speak
a high
mountain tie it around the mountain and
you go you can throw a
planet but he says 1 million planet
okay uh okay last part of
uh that bodh can look at the Buddhist uh
on all the planets they can look at the
Buddhas on all planets and and and
listen to their teaching from here can
stay
here and can listen to what they're
teaching and can also see what all the
living beings are doing
non and at that same time can see what
is their past
life yeah so that's all number
15 I think it was the King right
can the the Boda see all this during
their meditation or even they come out
of meditation they can still see I don't
think they have to be in meditation cuz
Clairvoyance is uh doesn't have to be in
meditation those five
Clairvoyance
okay he didn't
say and I'm not sure it relates to
level but there's another
writer who lived uh 100 years
later and he divide uh those 22 sorry
all he divided the different kinds of
body
CH according to uh which of the 10 body
sappa levels
you so somebody trying it somebody
trying it his name is
Jim and he wrote a separate book about
the
22 so I read that for a long time but
then I saw is
[Laughter]
better uh but I someday if you want to
learn that one we can do it's not too
long it's 25 pages
long it would be nice to
translate it's a nice essay the whole
books about
bod it's an essay on
bod and he talks about that and it's
here but we won't have
time uh
uh what do we always say at the end of
the
class so the second line means uh
if you do something with understanding
King uh we don't call Good Karma or Bad
Karma we call collect we call preparing
your Buddha body and
mind preparing Buddha body and
mind it's called collection of good
and a collection of wisdom it's its name
is not Karma we cannot use the word what
a Buddha does is not
Karma we have a different
word it's called collection of good and
collection of
wisdom col col
wisdom yeah very famous in that prayer
you know because the collection of good
creates a budh
body and the collection of wisdom
creates a Buddhist
mind so if you start collecting those
two sets of
causes it's like a treasure
house yeah so that's number 16 is called
a treasure house
and it also has to do with
u offering Sun means to offer food to
the
monks offering food to the
monks and offering flowers the
among uh which are always way to respect
respect
s
uh and it's also the desire
to give everybody the body and mind of a
Buddha
so in Kam's
commentary you know Buddha told
uhti you should put everybody into
Nana should put everybody into
n where there is no body or
mind
then says we have to be careful with
this word no body no mind
the lower
school say when you reach
nirvana uh you have no body you have no
mind uh but the higher
school and especially
Tantra say at that time
your your body turns into uh
Buddha and the four parts of your mind
turn into Buddha and these are the five
Buddha
four parts of my become Buddha it's
actually three and a half but it's
okay okay so it's not that you lose your
body in
mind you lose your dirty body in
mind okay that's all that's
16 uh
17 what is that
Joanna oh yeah it's at a
Highway uh in Sanskrit mahamar something
like that let me check actually let me
let me check that uh the Sanskrit is
yeah
mahamar uh it means big Road
we had Marga this weekend in Hong Kong
Karma Marga path of
karma so Maha means big right M like
Mahayana so big path so it should be
like a highway or
something
uh at let me see
[Music]
then this is the highway they always
call it in in the Buddhist book they
always say the highway which was
traveled by all the Buddhist suffice and
Buddhist before
Oh and will be traveled by all the
Buddhist and body body service in the
future
uh yeah that's
easy
18 yeah this a difficult one
um sh suble uh the
Sanskrit word
is a the Sanskrit word here is
Yana in the in the original in the
original verse and I can give him the
all this this
stuff these are the I can give you the
file but this is this this is a s
verses and I put the
numbers so 18 is so this the word here
is Yana the
original by mrea
so you know
Mahayana big
vehicle so usually it's like a horse or
something okay uh or a
cart okay uh and uh here
uh he said uh
it says a a good
vehicle uh that doesn't fall into the
two sides of the you know the when you
have a road and you have two ditches on
the
side then
uh we we say it doesn't fall into to the
two
extremes uh one
problem is to think it's okay I can live
like I used to
[Music]
live and the other problem is uh if I
reach nirvana I will
disappear so then a a good car doesn't
fall into either idea
and like like maybe it's okay to live
like
this you know don't use
seeds then the other problem is
the I reach n and I will
disappear so what this meaning
is to avoid we call avoid the two EXT
the two Cliffs this a cliff
right yeah
then that's a definition of middle
way uh don't follow up don't don't
follow off this
Cliff everything exists the way I see
it's coming this
way then the other Cliff is uh if it
doesn't exist this
way then it's then it's not
real okay cool middle way is uh coming
from me
but it's
real I asked the Hong Kong people you
know if the pen is coming from my mind
is it
real then they said they look confused
you know I don't I say come here I give
a guy
mustard I said look it's real it's
coming from your
mind but it's
real in the monastery
uh I told you many times if you say uh
if you say even though it's coming from
my mind it's
real they will hit
you uh you have to say because it's
coming from my mind is
[Music]
real yeah I like that uh so number
18 is like a a good vehicle
it doesn't go off this
way here's the road and it doesn't fall
off the
road this one is the cup is coming from
the
cup and this one is uh if the cups
coming from me it's not
real yeah but a good car or good horse
stays in the middle
and that's the definition of middle
[Music]
way yeah you okay you have some okay
it's your tea yeah you got we almost
finished maybe we go some sleep
today Veronica say I have to
finish she said you always take from Mr
will you never give him
something we almost finished down okay
uh okay this one is cool uh it's
a water from a spring
Pion what do you call that water from
the spring spring comes up from under
the ground the water P okay
uh and it and it
means uh the body
CH which has the power to remember the
all the details of the
DH and not
forget and teach to others without any
effort uh to topaa
means with no uh
block what is it in
Sanskrit to teach with no block
like just can talk like that you
know it's
a yeah yeah so he's playing here it's
his
[Laughter]
name means no
block can talk just like this you
know so number
19 is the
spring and uh it means the can remember
all the
Dharma and teach it like a spring you
just keep
going then he says
uh a goes
deeper he says
uh there are two kinds of
Springs one is uh this one that
goes you know it goes from the bottom it
goes up in the
air and other kind of spring we have a
DI Mountain
uh the Water we call in English we say
the water seeps out of the
stones and uh if you take the water it
then next morning it will it will slowly
come
back it doesn't go like this you
know then uh a says this is the one that
goes like this
why and and in and in the
Sanskrit it's a special kind of spring
it's not usual kind of
spring let me check the
Sanskrit it is uh we
call
[Music]
PR when you spread your feet in a POS
and you you you do a forward bend it's
called PR
Prana and samsara comes from the same
word
spread uh so anyway uh it means this
kind of
special and then he says
um he says something cool he says
the it
includes the Dharma which people heard
before in the world
and it includes the Dharma which the
people haven't heard
before so the water that is still
hidden mean the Dharma which nobody
heard recently in the
world and the the water which is already
visible it's a Dharma which people
already heard in this world
and that bu is St inside is
B so they are pouring the one but half
is people never saw
before and half is people saw
before I like it and it never
ends
okay I like that
one he he has a long explanation of the
two kinds of
spring took me a long time to study it
he quotes a very old book about two
kind okay number
20 yeah it's called danan it means a
Sweet Sound but it also meant
guitar
uh and there's a very famous uh Co
Buddhist
poem it's a four
lines and it's called chy DOI uh the the
four principles of the Dharma is your
fora
and
uh it's actually the test of a Buddhist
book if the Buddhist book is talk about
the four it's a Buddhist book if it
doesn't talk about the four it's not a
Budd and we studied it in ACI a long
time
ago I have to always look it up again
you know
very famous first
one uh anything which has a cause will
die anything which is not pure will give
you
pain uh nothing is
itself and uh only Nirvana is piece the
only piece
is this is very if the book doesn't talk
about that it's not a Buddhist
book then when you tell that to
somebody if they really understand
it it sounds beautiful as a as the song
of a
guitar and this body thought can declare
it on many planets at the same
time okay
21 uh major
river like like young
R
rer uh
so a river doesn't care who touches
it it's equal to all
people like everybody can drink water
and everybody can wash and ref
wash their body in
the the river doesn't say I like you I
don't like
you uh and that River of uh love from
bodh
sat uh never
stops uh it always helps
others it combines many smaller rivers
of ways to help people
and
uh it
understands that the mind and the object
of the Mind are the
same then some people didn't understand
that and they said oh this is my mind or
something like that uh but it's not what
Buddha meant
here is that uh the mind that sees the
cup and the cup which the Mind sees
both coming from the same
scene so here's the
seed planted I don't know last
week then time time time time time then
the seed opens into Michael and the
cup so if I understand that it's like a
powerful River
to help
people so I like this
one
uh then he talks about how the river
treats everybody
equal uh he says uh people who are
blind people who are
de people who are
crazy uh people who take off their
clothes and run around like crazy it
happened to in my llama's class one
time one guy got crazy he took off his
clothes then my said I'm going upstairs
you take care of
it then he took all the llamas
things and he carefully he made a big
mountain in the middle of the church in
the middle of the
temple then we had to call the police
you
know anyway that River doesn't care even
if you are that crazy the river still
treat you
equal those who are
hungry those who are
thirsty those who became
animal Hungry Ghost
H still teach all of them
equally River doesn't say I won't wash
you you
know 22 then we go to B
maybe yeah
clown and that's the highest
one uh
then uh in the
sky uh the clouds will first there's no
clouds uh then the clouds will start to
form and grow right and and then they
will
disappear you and then no more
clo so it means uh this is the highest
kind of body
St has the highest body ch
uh can stay in like amabas paradise or
we call T T
G and then sometimes they form a
cloud it means emanate to the
Earth and they pretend to do the 12
Deeds
of pretend it's always pretend
there are this Buddha in on our
world he was Buddha before he came
here but he pretend to be born as a
prince he pretend to see
suffering he pretend to run
away he pretend to
many pretend to become Buddha then
pretend to die
uh 12
de and we say just all he's pretending
then like a
clown so Cloud come to the
sky
born grow
up become
Buddha and
die but it's all just his play his
plan uh to show us what we have to
do uh like a
clown and that's
all there's a one funny part
here last one here all the Sutra here
says that person will pretend to do all
the things that the Buddha
does including looking at things like an
elephant looks at
things and that's the last sentence in
the Sut from which the 22 came the
20,000
verses 25,000
verses so that the source of the of AAS
was an older
Center and someday we can have fun and
read it you
know it's about 20
pages but the last sentence is uh when
you come to this world as a Buddha you
will look at things the way the elephant
looks at
things then I like uh what's that you
know and uh I check I can use our
database you know I can use search
program and I can say what does that
mean and in in one minute I can I can
search 15,000
books and I found it I thought you I'll
read it to you it's
fun I I cut it you can use a search b
cut it out put it in here you
know what does it mean to look at things
like an
elephant
uh so this there's a Sutra that talks
about
it don't look at things about
we don't bend your neck and look
down don't look at things to the left
and right like
that no don't move your head like
this don't do that and don't twist your
neck and look at the things behind
you and uh don't try to see what's the
farway and don't look too close a thing
you
know uh
just
see it means a see see
emptiness it means don't don't try very
hard it's just like and then see
emptiness so I that's how elephant
looks I like that
one it means you try too hard to see
him and you won't see
it uh but if you just relax and
that's how elephant
looks that's
all yeah good
[Applause]